Guide to the Liggett Family Papers TAM.463
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- St. Paul Public Library: archival materials on the death of Walter W. Liggett (copies) (Box 13)
- St. Paul Union Advocate: articles and notes (copies) (Box 13)
- Saturday Press (Minneapolis): notes, articles (copies) (Box 13)
- Research papers on Walter Liggett and Floyd Olson (Box 13)
- Western Worker: notes and photocopies of information on Scottsboro trials (Box 13)
- United Action: notes and photocopies of articles (Box 13)
- Series of clippings from newspapers, including Wilmar Tribune and US Farm News Research: childhood development theory and child abuse (Box 13)
- FBI materials re: Frank Nitti (copies) (Box 13)
- FBI materials re: Crime in Minneapolis (copies) (Box 13)
- Marda L. Woodbury: writing samples and job-searching materials (Box 13)
- Stopping the Presses: binder of press and publication materials, including book reviews (Box 13)
- Marda L. Woodbury, "Death of a Newsman," article copes with editorial comments and notes (Box 13)
- Walter W. Liggett, "Pioneers of Justice," Photocopy of book (Box 13)
- Marda L. Woodbury, "Youth Information Resources" notes and photocopies, research (Box 13)
- Virginia Seiden: information and letters re: literary execution responsibilities (Box 13)
- Virginia Seiden: Love and Revolution, photocopies of novel manuscript (Box 13)
- Marda L. Woodbury, "Youth Information Resources": ideas and research for related articles/books" (Box 14)
- "Youth Information Resources" promotional materials (Box 14)
- "Youth Information Resources" research and newspaper clippings (Box 14)
- Stopping the Presses: drafts and notes for individual chapters (Box 14)
- Stopping the Presses: book reviews, copies of newspaper clippings (Box 14)
- Stopping the Presses: research and notes on vice in Minneapolis and Farmer-Labor party (newspaper clippings and copies) (Box 14)
- Stopping the Presses: two folder of photocopied illustrations (Box 14)
- Walter W. Liggett, "Fire" (short story) (Box 14)
- Research: investigation of the muder of Walter Liggett, copies of: FBI reports, police reports, investigation of the justice department, investigation of Assistant Attorney General Pike (St. Paul) (Box 15)
- Research: Frank "The Enforcer" Nitti (Box 15)
- Research: Kid Cann and guns used in murder (Box 15)
- Research: transcripts of interviews with witnesses and court testimony (Box 15)
- Research: police investigation, letters (Box 15)
- Stopping the Presses: copy of table of contents (Box 15)
- Marda L. Woodbury: "Assassination of an Editor", essay and article drafts (Box 15)
- Stopping the Presses: drafts and notes on individual chapters, preface, and acknowledgements (Box 15)
- Research: Pasco, Washington, notes, newspaper articles (copies) (Box 15)
- Draft: information on Third Party and Left-of-Center politics (Box 16)
- Research: Chicago Tribune articles about the murder of Liggett (Box 16)
- Common Sense articles (Box 16)
- Daily Worker articles (Box 16)
- Duluth News Tribune articles (Box 16)
- Wefald (Knud) Papers Minnesota Historical Society, Williams Papers (copies) (Box 16)
- Interviews: Marda L. Woodbury and Judge MacKinnon, Robert Wilson, transcripts (Box 16)
- The American Press (newsletter), article on Liggett murder (Box 16)
- Research: Fargo Courier-News (Box 16)
- Edith Liggett: columns in the Midwest American, written under pseudonym Rena Gunderson (Box 16)
- Editor and Publisher: articles on the death of Walter Liggett (Box 16)
- Research: war and fascism, copies of newspaper articles (Box 16)
- Research: Smith Act and US Communism (Box 16)
- Research: Teamster Strike (1934) (Box 16)
- Research: Russian Famine Relief: copies of archival materials from the Newberry Library (Box 16)
- Research: Sacco and Vanzetti, copies of parts of books and newspaper articles (Box 16)
- Research: Sen. Thomas Schall (MN), comments on the murder of Liggett (Box 16)
- Research: Prohibition, copies of articles and parts of books (Box 16)
- Tacoma, book of postcards (Box 16)
- Research: Marlin Pew, copies of artciels (Box 16)
- Research: Hjalmar Petersen (ed-Askov MN American Papers) (Box 16)
- Research: National Archives re: Sen. Thomas Schall (copies) (Box 17)
- Research: Meyer Schuldberg, owner of MN liquor plant criticized by Liggett (copies of articles) (Box 17)
- Research: Tamiment Library re: Bill and Lucy Sheehan (copies) (Box 17)
- Research: Sen. Henrik Shipstead (copies of book) (Box 17)
- Research: ACLU Archives re: F. Shoemaker (copies) (Box 17)
- Research: Lilly Library re: Upton Sinclair (copies) (Box 17)
- Research: re Floyd Olson, drafts of essays, copies of articles (Box 17)
- Research: re assassination plots of JFK and RFK (Box 17)
- Research: Third Party politics (Box 17)
- Research: Author Townley, parts of books and articles (copies) (Box 17)
- Research: Prohibition, copies of articles (Box 17)
- Quotations: lists of quotations from left-leaning leaders (Box 17)
- Research: Grand Forks American articles (copies) (Box 17)
- Research: MN newspapers (Box 17)
- Research: The Modern Monthly and The Nation re: Liggett murder (Box 17)
- Marda L. Woodbury, diploma for MA at UC-Berkeley (Box 17)
- Folder of cartoons re: Nonpartisan League (Box 17)
- Burton Wheeler, Speech on Nicaragua (printed booklet) (Box 17)
- Walter Liggett, "Out on his Feet" (Box 17)
- Walter Liggett, "Five Poems" (Box 17)
- Walter Liggett, essay on 1920 campaign (Box 17)
- Walter Liggett, "The Firebug" (Box 17)
- Walter Liggett, "The Failure" (Box 17)
- Common Sense vol. 1 no.8 (Box 17)
- Information on genealogy (flyers and pamphlets) (Box 17)
- North Dakota History vol. 54 no. 2 (Box 17)
- Materials on tourism in North Dakota (Box 17)
- Research: Joseph Gilbert (Box 18)
- Research: Minnesota Historical Society (Box 18)
- Research: Nonpartisan League (Box 18)
- Stopping the Presses: draft of chapters with editorial notes (Box 18)
- Research: murder of Walter Liggett, articles and court transcripts (copies) (Box 18)
- Research: Minnesota Farmer-Labor Party (copies of books) (Box 18)
- Folder of photographs of the Liggett family (Box 18)
- Photocopies of The Midwest American (Box 18)
- Issues of Editor and Publisher (Box 19)
- Supreme Court of NY record, Walter Liggett v. Herbert Corey & Houghton Mifflin (Box 19)
- Copy of "The People's Chronology" by James Trager (copy) (Box 19)
- Supreme Court of MN record, Frank Ellis v. State of MN (Box 19)
- Photocopies of the Daily Worker (Box 19)
- FBI files on Fred Ossanna (copies) (Box 19)
- Supreme Court of NY record, Edith Liggett v. Comprodaily Publishing Company, Inc. (Box 19)
- 3 VHS tapes of Marda L. Woodbury TV appearances (Box 19)
- 4 cassette tapes: interview Morns Forhosch on Edith Liggett, "Soundtrack: Liggett," Joe Murphy on Walter Liggett, 1936 Floyd Olson speech (Box 19)
- 8 CDs of interviews (Box 19)
- Bound volume of photostats from Edith Liggett's 1938 suit against Comprodaily Publishing Company, which published the Daily Worker, titled: "Photostats of Exhibits Pursuant to Stipulation." (Box 20)